Guide to the Department of History Records, 1932-[ongoing] UA.25.23.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Course Papers, 1954-2003, bulk 1966-1992, 7 boxes
  - Richard Watson course papers, 1954-1995
    - History 114
      - Baker, Catherine. "My Father's Experience as a Medical Officer during World War II." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Becker, Helaine. "Growing Up-Wartime." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Blackwell, Lee Banks. "The Stock Market Crash to WWII: As seen by George Lawrence Blackwell." (1984) (Box 6)
      - Bowser, Charles E. "Depression during the 1920s-1930s." (1980) (Box 6)
      - Browne, Daryl. "The Thirties: A Family Perspective." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Caldwell, Bill. "America from 1920-1945." (interview and transcript, 1975) (Box 6)
      - Chopra, Hersh. "The Depression Years: Reflections of a Child." (1982) (Box 6)
      - Curtis, Amy L. "The Depression in Rural North Carolina 1928-1936: A Youth's Impression." (1982) (Box 6)
      - Frankel, Rachel. "A Personal Experience of the Great Depression." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Googe, Earl. "The Depression and the Innocence of Childhood." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Killorin, Bob. "The Depression in Hogansville: A Family History." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Malasky, Beth. "Between the Wars: A Childhood in Brooklyn." (1982) (Box 6)
      - Maron, Susan, Depression Era documents, undated (Box 6)
      - McFadden, Tom. "A New Life in the United States, 1928-1941." [1982?] (Box 6)
      - Montgomery, Sandy. "The Great Depression through the Eyes of a Rural Midwestern Family." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Neff, Anne M. "When God and Country Were More than Just Words." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Neppl, Gregory E. "An Analysis of a Child's Perspective of the Second World War." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Nichols, Randall. "Reflections of the Depression." (1982) (Box 6)
      - Quinton, Albert. "The Great Equalizer: A History of the Depression Years of 1929-1939 as Experienced by Relatives and Family Friends." (1980) (Box 6)
      - Schoff, Hilary. "James S. Schoff: A Personal History." (1982) (Box 6)
      - Shanahan, Maureen G. "Johnny Jones: A Black Man's Experience of the Depression Years." (1981) (Box 6)
      - Smith, Warren. "Three Important Days for a Young Girl." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Stanislaw, Jacqueline. "Andrew Verba: A Czechoslovakian Immigrant." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Thompson, Nanette Kellogg. "The Depression and My Family" (1979) (Box 6)
      - Wiggins, Connie. "Rural Education in North Carolina Year 1929." [1984?] (Box 6)
      - Young, David O. "From the Depression to the Draft: A Personal History." (1979) (Box 6)
      - Young, Terri. "Years of Struggle: One Woman's Struggle of the Depression." (1980) (Box 6)
    - History 191 (Box 7)
      - Heller, Jeffrey A. "Five Immigrants to Northern New York: The How, the Why, and the Wherefore." (1975) (Box 7)
    - History 195/196
      - Burwell, Jack. "A Study of Metropolitan Voter Patterns in the Presidential and Gubernatorial Races in North Carolina from 1928 to 1968." (1969) (Box 7)
      - Kimball, John. "Municipal Government Reform in Durham, 1913-1921: Upper-Class Progressivism." (1970) (Box 7)
      - McClatchey, Bill. "The Early History of Public Health in Durham, North Carolina Through 1920." (1969) (Box 7)
    - History 278
      - Stichel, H. Mark. "'Stirring up the Fires of Race Antipathy': The Summary of John Spencer Bassett's Early Writing and Thought." (1979) (Box 7)
    - History 308
      - Devine, Thomas A. "The Image v. The Reality: Negroes, Desegregation, and the University of North Carolina, 1934-1963." (1979) (Box 7)
      - Nesmith, Vardell E. "The Evolution of American Field Artillery Doctrine to 1904." (1974) (Box 7)
    - History 351
      - Paddock, Jr., Alfred H. "Alfred Thayer Mahan: His Influence on the Foreign and Defense Policy of Theodore Roosevelt." (1972) (Box 7)
    - [History?]
      - Speedy, III, John C. "Mexican Bandits and the Technological Adaptation of the U.S. Army to Motor Vehicles, 1916." (1972) (Box 7)
    - Honors Papers
      - Avery, Sally. "Public Welfare and Durham County." (1969) (Box 7)
      - Harrington, David. "The Dillingham Commission Properly Understood." (1984) (Box 7)
    - Independent Study
      - Palermo, John. "The Killings of November Third in Greensboro: An Obstruction of Justice." (1983) (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Fair, Bryan K. "The Allen Building Takeover: Origins of Black Student Protests at Duke University, 1966-1969." (1982) (Box 7)
      - Jeffers, Thomas W. "Duke University: Academia Wrestling with its Soul, 1924-1987." (1987) (Box 7)
      - Morrin, Douglas S. "Segregation at Duke Hospital, 1930-1995." (1995) (Box 7)
- Subject Files, 1947-2002, 3 boxes
  Subject files contain a sampling of various departmental material. Subjects include directories, handbooks, minutes and memoranda, and newsletters. Also present is a small publication, "Historical Background of the World Today," a brief history of the modern world published by Duke University Press, and Research Notes in which departmental faculty discuss their general research interests as well as current research and work.
  - Alumni Register, "History as the Background of Today: Teaching Approach brings History to Life for Duke Freshman," 1953 (Box 8)
  - Announcements-general departmental, 1961-1977 (Box 8)
  - Departmental Planning, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
  - Directory-faculty members, 1961-1963 (Box 8)
  - Directory-graduate students, 1962-1975 (Box 8)
  - Director of Graduate Studies-annual report, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Employment Notices (unavailable candidates), 1962-1977 (Box 8)
  - Handbook-department, 2001-2002 (Box 8)
  - Handbooks-graduate, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Historical Conferences and Symposiums, 1947, 1956, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Honors Program, 1968, 1978, undated (Box 8)
  - Departmental Memoranda (3 Folders), 1955-1973 (Box 8)
  - Departmental Memoranda, 1974-1978 (Box 9)
  - Memoranda and Reports-miscellaneous, 1984 May-1986 May (Box 9)
  - Memoranda to Graduate Students, 1965-1973 (Box 9)
  - Memoranda to Undergraduates, 1959-1969 (Box 9)
  - Minutes-Faculty Meeting, 1974 Sept.-1975 Sept. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1951, 1960-1979 (Box 9)
  - Newsletter (2 Folders), 1949 Feb.-1977 April (Box 9)
  - Newsletter, 1978 April-2000 July (Box 10)
  - Publications, "Historical Background of the World Today: A Synopsis," by Harold Parker and Theodore Ropp (Box 10)
  - Reading Lists and Course Examinations, 1952-1967 (Box 10)
  - Research Notes, 1982-1984 (Box 10)
  - Reports-departmental, 1958-1974 (Box 10)
  - Schedules of Courses, 1957-1969 (Box 10)
  - Statistics, 1958-1960, 1974-1978 (Box 10)
  - Subject Outline, Dr. Paul H. Clyde, History 141/142, undated (Box 10)
- Administrative Files, 1932-1985, 22 boxes
  Administrative Records of the Department of History document the daily operations of the Department and faculty members. The records are divided into four subseries: Office of the Chair, Director of Graduate Study, Director of Undergraduate Study, and Search Committee records. The records are arranged alphabetically and in the order in which they were accessioned.
  - Office of the Chair, 1951-1985
    This subseries contains material created and accumulated by the departmental Office of the Chair. In addition to the Chair, some of the material was accumulated by the administrative assistant to the chairman and therefore encompasses the tenures of several individual departmemtal Chairs. Material present includes correspondence and intra-office memoranda concerning job applicants and faculty appointments, course evaluations, conferences and seminars, recommendations and promotions, departmental budget material, and correspondence with various University Presidents and Deans. Also present are minutes and notes from various committees including American Committee for the Study of War Documents, Committee on Courses, Curriculum and Long-Range Planning, and Committee on Honors and Graduate Placement. Major subjects include American Historical Association and Review, Southern Historical Association, Commonwealth Studies Center, Inter-university Consortium for Political Research (ICPR), Social Sciences Council, Trinity College Historical Society, the Humanities and Russian Cooperative with the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, and National Defense Education Act. Chairmanships in this subseries include William T. Laprade (1937-1952), Charles Sydnor (1952-1954), E. Malcolm Carroll (1954-1957), John R. Alden (1957-1960), Richard L. Watson (1960-1967, acting Chair 1971-), Joel Colton (1967-1970), and Anne F. Scott.
    - Administrative (President Edens), 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - Alden, Prof. John, 1957 (Box 11)
    - American Committee for the Study of War Documents (ACSWD)
      - Sub-Committee on Microfilming, 1955 (Box 11)
      - Sub-Committee on Microfilming, 1956 Jan.-1956 July (Box 11)
      - Sub-Committee on Microfilming, 1956 Aug.-1956 Dec. (Box 11)
      - ACSWD, 1957 (Box 11)
    - American Historical Association (AHA), undated (Box 11)
    - AHA, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - AHA, meeting, 1956 (Box 11)
    - American Historical Review, 1954 (Box 11)
    - Announcements of Graduate Awards, 1953-1955 (Box 11)
    - "Calendar" Announcements, 1954 (Box 11)
    - Applicatons, 1953 Oct.-1954 Aug., 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Applications-General, 1954-1956 Sept., 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Applications-Positions, 1956-1959, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Appointments Office Recommendations, 1954-1956, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - A-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954 (Box 11)
    - A-Outgoing, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Bills for Purchase of Reprints (Faculty), 1955-1956 (Box 11)
    - Bell, J. Bowyer, 1957 (Box 11)
    - Blazer Lectures (University of Kentucky), 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - Book Reviews, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - B-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1957 (Box 11)
    - Carroll, E. Malcolm (Personal), 1954-1957 (Box 11)
    - Clyde, Prof. Paul H., 1956 (Box 11)
    - Colton, Prof. Joel G., 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - Committee on Courses of Instruction, 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - Committee on Historians and the Federal Government, 1957 (Box 11)
    - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
    - Edens, Pres. A. Hollis, 1954 (Box 11)
    - Course Schedule, spring 1958 (Box 11)
    - Crittenden, Christopher, 1957 (Box 11)
    - C-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1959 (Box 11)
    - Davis, Prof. Rodney O., 1955-1958 (Box 11)
    - Dean Hobbs, Marcus and Anne Inman, 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - Departmental Correspondence (Carroll), 1954 Feb.-1955 June (Box 11)
    - Department of History Roster, 1953-1960 (Box 11)
    - Department Letters, 1959-1960 (Box 11)
    - Director of Summer Session, 1954-1956 (Box 11)
    - Durden, Prof. Robert F., 1956 (Box 11)
    - D-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1959 (Box 11)
    - Economic Research Committee, 1957 (Box 11)
    - Epstein, Dr. Fritz T., 1955 (Box 11)
    - Examinations-Preliminary and Final, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
    - E-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - E-Miscellaneous Letters, 1957, 1959 (Box 11)
    - History Faculty Correspondence, 1955 May-1956 May (Box 11)
    - Flowers Collection Committee, 1955 (Box 11)
    - French History Conference, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Freshmen Advisors, 1953-1954 (Box 11)
    - Freshmen-Sophomore Advisors, 1955 (Box 11)
    - F-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954, 1957 (Box 11)
    - Graduate Assistants, 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - Graduate Bulletins, 1957-1958 (Box 11)
    - Graduate School-Prof. Charles Ward (Box 11)
    - Graduate Students in History (2 folders), 1955-1957 (Box 11)
    - Grants-Miscellaneous, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
    - Gross, Paul M.-Vice-President, 1957-1958 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence-Gross, Paul M., 1954-1955 (Box 11)
    - G-Miscellaneous Letters, 1956-1959 (Box 11)
    - Henricksen, G.C., 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - History Department (Departmental Matters), 1956-1967 (Box 12)
    - History Department Meetings, 1953-1955 (Box 12)
    - History Department-First Meeting, Fall 1954 (Box 12)
    - History Department-Second Meeting, 1954 November (Box 12)
    - History Department-Second Meeting, 1955 April (Box 12)
    - History Department-First Meeting, 1955 October (Box 12)
    - History Department-Second Meeting, 1955 November (Box 12)
    - History Department-Third Meeting, 1956 February (Box 12)
    - History Faculty Meeting-First Meeting, 1956 October (Box 12)
    - History Department-Minutes, 1958 (Box 12)
    - History Staff Publications, 1951-1957, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Hobbs, Marcus (Dean of Graduate School), 1957, 1959 (Box 12)
    - Hollyday, Frederick B.M., 1956 (Box 12)
    - Honors Committee/Seminar Room Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - H-Miscellaneous Letter, 1954-1959, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - I-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Johnson, Dr. Allen, 1957 (Box 12)
    - J-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1957, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - King, Prof. Doris Elizabeth, 1958 (Box 12)
    - K-Miscellaneous Letters, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
    - Library Matters, 1956 (Box 12)
    - L-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1958, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Magenis, Alice, 1957 (Box 12)
    - Manuscript (Letters, etc.), 1956 (Box 12)
    - Maps Committee, 1954 (Box 12)
    - Sub-Committee on Alexandria Microfilming Project (AMP)-Dr. Weinberg, 1956 (Box 12)
    - Sub-Committee on AMP-Recruiting of Microfilming Staff, 1956 (Box 12)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1954 (Box 12)
    - Murray, John A., 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - M-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1957, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - McCloy, Prof. Shelby, 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - Mc-Miscellaneous Letters, 1955-1956, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Newsletter Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 12)
    - N-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954, 1957 (Box 12)
    - O-Miscellaneous Letters, 1956 (Box 12)
    - Parker, Prof. Harold T. (Director of Undergraduate Studies), 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Placement Requests (other humanities), 1956 (Box 12)
    - Placement Testing, 1953-1954 (Box 12)
    - Publication Subsidies, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - P-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1959, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Recommendations for Grants and Fellowships, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Recommendations, 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - Recommendations for Positions, 1954-1956, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Re: Registration, 1954 (Box 12)
    - Research Project for Bennett Place, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - Requests-Sabbatical, 1954-1956 (Box 12)
    - Rock, Prvt. William, 1955-1957 (Box 12)
    - R-Miscellaneous, 1954-1956, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Schedules, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Schedule of Courses, fall 1955 (Box 12)
    - Scholarships, undated (Box 12)
    - Shafer, Dr. Boyd (AHA), 1957 (Box 12)
    - Smith, Edward (American Book Co.), 1957 (Box 12)
    - Smith, Dr. James (Institute of Early American History & Culture), 1957 (Box 12)
    - Sciences Research Council (Committee on Grants-in-Aid), 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - Southern Historical Association (SHA) Meeting, 1954 (Box 12)
    - SHA, 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - Stark, John D., 1957 (Box 12)
    - State Library and Historical Association of N.C., 1957 (Box 12)
    - Student Guide to Duke Faculty, undated (Box 12)
    - Summer Seminar in American Diplomatic History, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
    - S-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1958 (Box 12)
    - Thompson, Robert L., 1957 (Box 12)
    - Tyler, George T., 1956 (Box 12)
    - T-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1958 (Box 12)
    - U-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Undergraduate Faculty, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
    - Visiting Professors (Second Semester), 1956-1957 (Box 12)
    - Whittford, W.E., 1954-1956 (Box 12)
    - W-Miscellaneous Letters, 1954-1958, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - News on Department Budget, undated (Box 12)
    - Academic Council, 1962-1969 (Box 13)
    - Administration Aid Book, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Advanced Placement, 1961-1963, undated (Box 13)
    - Advanced Placement Formulas, 1970 (Box 13)
    - Aldin, Prof. John R., 1965-1969 (Box 13)
    - American Historical Association-membership directory, 1970 (Box 13)
    - American Historical Review, 1961-1965 (Box 13)
    - American Historical Conventions, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
    - Asian Studies, 1961, 1962 (Box 13)
    - Applications-Departmental Positions, 1965-1968, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Appointments Office, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Appointments
      - Appointments, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Miscellaneous, 1960-1963 (Box 13)
      - Appointments (2 Folders), 1963-1966 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-American, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-American foreign relations, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Chinese language, 1962-1966 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Commonwealth, 1962-1964 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Comparative Government and Constitutional Law, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-East Asia, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-English, 1961-1964 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Far East, 1960-1964 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-History of Science, 1961-1964, undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Appointments-History of Japan, 1966, undated (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Latin America, 1963, 1966 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Political Behavior, 1963 (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Renaissance, 1960-1962, 1964, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Appointments-Russian, 1960-1961, 1966, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Appointments-U.S. History, 1963-1965 (Box 13)
    - B-Miscellaneous, 1959-1968 (Box 13)
    - Behavioral Science, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Bronfenbrenner, Prof. Martin (vita), undated (Box 13)
    - Bulletins-Departmental, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Bulletins-Undergraduate, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
    - Bulletin Copy-Undergraduate, 1974-1975 (Box 13)
    - Bureau of Public Information (DU), 1957 (Box 13)
    - Calendar-Meetings of interest to Historians, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Calendars-Duke University, 1964 Sept.-1965 Feb. (Box 13)
    - Careers in Government, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
    - Chairmen of Departments, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Chinese, 1961-1966, bulk 1962-1963 (Box 13)
    - Codes, 1960, 1963, undated (Box 13)
    - Cole, R. Taylor (Provost), 1963 (Box 13)
    - C-Miscellaneous, 1960-1967 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Calkins, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Ferguson, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Hollyday, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Lerner, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Miller, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Parker, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Course Evaluations-Rolf, 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Evaluations-Scott, A., 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Evaluations-Scott, W., 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Evaluations-TePaske, 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Evaluations-Witt, 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Evaluations-Young, 1973 (Box 14)
    - Course Offerings, 1963-1965 (Box 14)
    - Course Schedules, 1959 Fall-1973 Fall, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Course Statistics, 1961-1965 (Box 14)
    - Courses-Introductory, 1961-1966 (Box 14)
    - Curriculum Committee (Planning), 1960 (Box 14)
    - D-Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Danforth Apprentice Teaching Program, 1966-1971 (Box 14)
    - Danforth Foundation Proposal, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Business, 1960-1964 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Committees, 1964-1969 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Committee Appointments, 1960-1969 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Planning, 1966 (Box 14)
    - Long-Range Planning Committee, 1958-1964, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Departmental Committee on Honors, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Governance, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Departmental Memoranda, 1960-1969 May, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Departmental Notices, 1968-1973, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Departmental Notices (6 Folders), 1974-1979 Jan. (Box 15)
    - Departmental Meetings-Minutes, 1960-1969 (Box 15)
    - Departmental-Miscellaneous, 1959-1960, 1969-1971, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Duke University Annual Report, 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - E-Miscellaneous, 1960-1965 (Box 15)
    - Educational Faculty Committee, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Educational Facilities Lab Project, 1968 (Box 15)
    - Engineers, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - Evaluations, Learning Experience, undated (Box 15)
    - F-Miscellaneous, 1958-1966 (Box 15)
    - Financial Papers-Invoices, 1961-1967, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Freshman Advisory Program, 1961-1964 (Box 15)
    - Fulbright Awards, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
    - G-Miscellaneous, 1960-1968 (Box 15)
    - Goodwin, Crawford, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Graduate Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Graduate School-Admissions, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Graduate School-Inquiries, 1966 (Box 15)
    - Graduate Students-Correspondence, 1970 (Box 15)
    - Graduate Students-Job opportunities, 1960-1963, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Graduate Students-Letters to, 1962 (Box 15)
    - Graduate Students, Miscellaneous information, 1961-1965, and 1969-1970, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Historical Meetings, 1966 March-August (Box 15)
    - History Majors Committee, 1970 (Box 15)
    - Hobbs, Dean Marcus E., 1960-1963 (Box 15)
    - Honor Pledges, 1963 October (Box 15)
    - Honors-Masters, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Honors and Other Special Programs of Study, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Honors-Masters Program Report, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - Honors System Vote, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Inter-university Consortium for Political Research (ICPR), 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - ICPR-General policy, 1963-1965 (Box 15)
    - ICPR-Miscellaneous, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - ICPR-Summer Programs, 1965 (Box 15)
    - ICPR-Technical information, 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - Independent Study, 1970 (Box 15)
    - International Studies, 1966 (Box 15)
    - International Studies-Programs, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Job Circulars, PhDs, 1961-1969 (Box 16)
    - Journal of Asian Studies (JAS), 1965-1968 (Box 16)
    - Journal of Asian Studies-Mail, 1965-1967, undated (Box 16)
    - JAS-Purchase order, 1965 (Box 16)
    - JAS-Storeroom, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
    - JAS-Telephone, undated (Box 16)
    - Journal of Southern History, 1961-1967 (Box 16)
    - Knight, Pres. Douglas M., 1963 (Box 16)
    - Alfred A. Knopf Scholarship, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Latin American History Conference, 1957 (Box 16)
    - Library-Duke University, 1960-1963, 1966 (Box 16)
    - Majors-Undergraduate, 1956-1963 (Box 16)
    - Ming Biographical Project, 1962-1968 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous File, 1970 (Box 16)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1961-1963 (Box 16)
    - Medical Historian Training Program, 1966-1967 (Box 16)
    - Moving Requests, 1969 (Box 16)
    - NATO-Data, 1963 (Box 16)
    - NATO Professor, 1965-1966 (Box 16)
    - National Defense Education Act (NDEA)-Manuals, 1966-1968 (Box 16)
    - NDEA-Summer Institute, 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - North Carolina Department of Archives and History, 1961-1964 (Box 16)
    - North Carolina Historical Review, 1960-1964 (Box 16)
    - Nelson, Ernest William-Retirement Reception, 1965 (Box 16)
    - Alan Nevins Prize, 1961 (Box 16)
    - Office Equipment, 1959-1969 (Box 16)
    - Program II, 1969 (Box 16)
    - Publications-Faculty, 1957-1969, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Readers, Letters, 1963-1969 (Box 16)
    - Reading Lists, 1956, 1961, undated, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Recommendations-Foreign Appointments, 1960-1961, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Recommendations-Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 16)
    - Registration Information, 1959-1964 (Box 16)
    - Registration, 1959-1960, 1962-1966, 9 folders (Box 16)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Russian Studies, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Russian Cooperative with UNC-Chapel Hill, 1964-1966 (Box 16)
    - State University College, (NY), 1973 (Box 17)
    - Southern Americana Committee, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Sub-Committee on Curriculum, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Summer Session, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Textbook Order Form, undated (Box 17)
    - Training Center, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Trinity College Historical Society, 1965 (Box 17)
    - Undergraduate Bulletin, 1974 (Box 17)